Grégoire Mialon

École Normale Supérieure Département Informatique Paris, France		gregoire.mialon@inria.fr https://github.com/GregoireMialon https://gregoiremialon.github.io	
Research			
2018 - <i>Now</i>	Member of Sierra team and TlMain focus: learning with neurAlso working on Natural Lang	 Inria & École Normale Supérieure (Paris, France) - PhD student Member of Sierra team and Thoth team. Main focus: learning with neural networks when labelled data is scarce. Also working on Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Causal Inference. Advisors: Pr. Julien Mairal, Pr. Alexandre d'Aspremont. 	
2016 (5 mon	 Nuclear Science and Engineeri Built a fast model for prediction using finite elements and high p 	Massachussets Institute of Technology (Cambridge, MA) - Research Intern - Nuclear Science and Engineering, Offshore Floating Nuclear Plant group Built a fast model for predicting damage resulting from ship collisions using finite elements and high performance computing Advisors: Pr. Neil Todreas, Pr. Koroush Shirvan.	
Education			
2017 - 2018		Msc. Mathematics, Vision and Learning (MVA) st and most prestigious Master's program in eep Learning, NLP.	
2013 - 2017	- Founded in 1794, the École po		
2010 - 2013		e) - Preparatory Classes: Bachelor level tics, Physics to prepare top-level science	

Teaching

2018 - 2021 Université Paris-Dauphine (France) - Teacher (M2 MASH)

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning.

2016 - 2017 Lycée Saint-Louis (Paris, France) - Teaching Assistant in Preparatory Classes

Tutored and tested weekly students in physics for nationwide examination.

Job experience

2019 - 2020 Athling (Paris, France) - Consultant

Evaluating the impact of machine learning on commerce and distribution. This report was commissioned by the french Prospective Observatory for Trade.

2017 - 2018

eXplain (Paris, France) - Data Scientist, NLP

- eXplain (ex-Liegey Muller Pons) is a company focusing on electoral campaign technology. The company closely worked for the last two winners of the french presidential elections.
- Developed and sold an automated press analysis product relying on NLP.
- Managers: Pr. Vincent Pons, Arthur Muller (founders).

2015 (3 months)

Ministry for Foreign Affairs (Paris, France) - Civil Servant Intern

- Drafted notes on terrorism for diplomats and political leaders on a mission.
- Manager: Emmanuel Cocher.

Publications

- G. Mialon*, D. Chen*, A. d'Aspremont and J. Mairal. A Trainable Optimal Transport Embedding for Feature Aggregation and its Relationship to Attention (ICLR 2021).
- G. Mialon, A. d'Aspremont and J. Mairal. Screening Data Points for Empirical Risk Minimization via Ellipsoidal Regions and Safe Loss Functions (AISTATS 2020).
- A. Bietti*, G. Mialon*, D. Chen and J. Mairal. A Kernel Perspective for Regularizing Deep Neural Networks (ICML 2019).

Invited Talks

- Paris NLP Meetup, Virtual, 2021. How Natural Language Processing is shaping Machine Learning.
- Gatsby Unit, UCL, 2019. Screening Data Points for Empirical Risk Minimization via Ellipsoidal Regions and Safe Loss Functions.
- eXplain, Paris, 2019. Sample Screening in Machine Learning.

Services

- Currently organizing a reading group on Causal Inference for Inria.
- Reviewing: Neurips 2020 (Pre-registration experiment).

Past projects

- Data Challenge: Predicting cancer from DNA for Stéphane Mallat's Curse of Dimensionality course 2018 (ranked first decile).
- Built a Tweet normalizer and a Parser for Emmanuel Dupoux's NLP course.
- Data Challenge: Paris RAMP Drug Test Challenge 2017 (ranked first decile).

Awards and Fellowships

2016

EDF Énergies nouvelles Fellowship - for pursuing research at MIT.

2016

École polytechnique Outstanding Investment - for involvment in the campus life and in a microfinance non-profit organization.

Languages and Skills

French (mother tongue), English (TOEIC: 965/990), German (advanced). Python (advanced), Rowing (involved in student contests).